# LUSANDA TSILANA

JUNIOR PRODUCT ENGINEER



sanda.tsilana@gmail.com



Cape Town, South Africa



🛅 ) www.linkedin.com/in/lusandatsilana31



https://lusandatdev-3a669.web.app/

# PROFILE

I consider myself to be a hard worker. I am always driven to produce good quality work. Due to customer service/call center experience, I am accustomed to working with people and functioning in a fast paced environment. Due to my passion for health and technology, I am currently pursuing a BSc. in Applied Mathematics and Computer Science. I am a life-long learner – always willing to try, learn new things and I am able to take feedback.

### EDUCATION

#### UNIVERSITY OF SOUTH AFRICA

2022 - Current

Bsc. Applied Mathematics and Computer Science

### UNIVERSITY OF WESTERN CAPE

2018 - 2020

BSc. Biotechnology

#### HAROLD CRESSY HIGH SCHOOL

2013 - 2017

National Senior Certificate

# EXPERIENCE

#### PRODUCT ENGINEER INTERN

Company: ABSA GROUP

February 2024 - Current

Using JavaScript and AWS services to enhance system functionality, ensuring robust and scalable solutions. My contributions are coding, integrating databases, and utilizing APIs, all while emphasizing teamwork and project management. This approach allows me to deliver high-quality, efficient systems that meet the needs of users and the business.

### JUNIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Company: CAPACiTi, YOUNGLINGS

January 2023 - January 2024

I've navigated the Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) with proficiency, designing and developing fully functional websites and mobile applications. My practice extends to using databases and APIs, ensuring data exchange and functionality. Throughout this journey, I've adhered to the SDLC's structured approach, from requirements gathering and analysis to deployment and maintenance, delivering high-quality, user-centric solutions.

### SKILLS

- Web Design
- Front-end Development
- API Intergration
- Data Intergration
- AWS Services
- · Problem-Solving
- Sales

# EXPERIENCE

#### **CLINICAL TRIAL RECRUITER**

company: SUBJECTWELL

June 2021 - January 2023

Served as a service agent to provide details regarding clinical studies for health benefits. My role included conducting a medical screening to evaluate patient eligibility and transfer pre-qualified patient for further medical screening.

Achievements and Awards include:

- · Outstanding Quality Assurance
- Great Patient Engagement
- Good Time Management Skills
- Team Player

# REFERENCES

#### Salesh Harrysharan

Vice President at ABSA Group 067 405 7164 Salesh.Harrysharan@absa..africa

### Joshua Schell

Line Manager at Younglings Africa 061 465 6848 joshua.schell@younglings.africa

### Thandi Ndaba-Sher

Manager at Cape Innovation and Technology Initiative 084 806 3374 thandi@capaciti.org.za

### **Nicole Tina Sampson**

Operational Team Lead at Subjectwell 073 247 0876

Nicole.Tina. Sampson@subjectwell.com